here you as a former police officer how do you
вот ты как бывший полицейский как
rate how you
оцениваешь как ты
qualify with a poster this
квалифицируется с плакатом это
offense Of course I agree with this
правонарушение Конечно я согласен с этим
Yes I paid a 500 ruble fine for this I
Да Я заплатил 500 руб штрафа за это в
mean 500 ruble is hooliganism already this is
смысле 500 руб это хулиганство уже это
not 500 ruble is not hooliganism No this is not this Not even not even
не 500 руб это не хулиганство Нет это
no this is
это не это Даже даже не даже нет это
petty hooliganism Yes 500 ruble for the first
мелкое хулиганство Да 500 руб на первый
time 500 ruble for the second time will already
раз 500 руб на второй уже
be administrative liability hello sha Where are you from the city of Orel
будет привет ша Вы откуда город Орёл
Orel Yes Cool My father is from
Орёл Да Прикольно У меня отец родом из
Orel itself from Orel itself
Орла самого из самого орла
Yes Cool And from what area where in general where
Да Классно А с какого района где вообще
from I have never been there he was
откуда я там никогда не был он
born there it turns out
получается родился там
he went to study in Kharkov and then And
ээ поехал учиться в Харьков и потом А
his parents died already and he never
родители его умерли уже и он никогда не
came to this Orel and then I was
приезжал уже в этот Орёл а потом я
born Here in Kharkov and also like in
родился Тут в Харькове и как бы тоже в
Orel Kharkov Yes from Kharkov yes And I understand well
Орёл Харькова Да из Харькова да А понял
va also a million times there Yes Listen and
ну ва тоже миллион раз там Да Слушайте а
how do you Orel residents or as it should be
как вы орловчане или как правильно надо
said correctly feel about the fact that now
говорить относитесь к тому что сейчас
Russia Russia is at war with  Ukraine uh once again
Россия Россия воюет с Украиной э ещё раз
Uh how do you feel about the fact that Russia is
Ээ как вы относитесь к тому что Россия
fighting with
воюет с
Ukraine
Украиной
badly And why did Russia attack Ukraine
плохо А зачем Россия напала на Украину
But that's another question as if I'm not
А вот это уже другой вопрос как бы я не
much of a politician let's say so And me too but
особо политик скажем так да И я тоже но
how would I communicate with people I was just
как бы я общался с людьми я был как раз
on the border of the Kharkov region on the
таки на границе Харьковской области на
border it turns out Sudzhansky
границе получается вот Суджанский как
district Belovsky district on the border with the
раз район Беловский район на границе с
Sumy region I communicated with local
Сумской областью я общался с местными
residents And just when the
жителями Вот и как раз когда вот
Ukrainian DRG before the start of their own
украинский дрг ещё перед началом сво
entered the villages Well you don't know about this for sure I'll
заходили в посёлки Ну вы об этом точно
say this few people know it's just that I was
знаете скажу это немногие знают просто я
there we were building there I was a prora and were building a
там был мы там строили я прора и строили
fortified district so we communicated I was just
укре район вот общались мне просто было
interested in this half this is like in what or
интересно во это полу это типа в чем или
in the thirtieth year of the past
в тридцатом году
this is right before the very start of their own and that
былом это прямо перед самим началом сво
is then the war was already going on
а то есть тогда уже война шла
ugh so why is the war going on between Russia
фу так война с чего го идт между Россией
and Ukraine the EU for example yes well that is it
и украи ЕС например да ну то есть она
was there in the Donbass
была там на Донбассе
already here were in the Kursk and Belgorod
уже сюда были в курскую и Белгородскую
regions like already Zask guys
область как бы уже Заска ребята
tried it interesting  interesting And in what
пробовали интересно интересно А в каком
quantity did these guys jump into the
количестве Заска кали эти ребята в
Kursk region I can know the date the
курскую область я дату я могу знать
quantity I talked to people with local
количество я с людьми общался с местными
residents just and says Yes there were
жителями просто да и говорит Да вот были
moments here and they raised a fuss here and
моменты тут и кипиши поднимали тут а
why and why was it not anywhere in the news in
почему а почему нигде в новостях в
Russia only this locals
России не было только вот это местные
said something I don’t know honestly
что-то говорили я не знаю честно говоря
I’m telling you that that is I’m telling
я же вам говорю что то есть я вот говорю
you what I know what people told me
вам то что знаю я что мне люди говорили
Yeah Well and these people could not figure it out
Угу Ну а это люди могли не разобраться
or they directly saw Ukrainian DRG
или они как прямо видели украинское дрг
I’ll tell you so in the
я вам скажу так в
border area people speak
приграничье люди разговаривают на
Surzhik you know what Surzhik is you know for sure
суржике знаете что такое Суржик точно
and Ukrainian soldiers
знаете и вот украинских солдат от
would have
российских бы
distinguished themselves from Russian border guards who communicate like that that
отличились приграничных кто так общается
is in Ukrainian Well this is not a language it’s
то есть на украинской Ну это не мова это
Surzhik Yes Russians do not communicate with na sushi that
Суржик Да русские с на суши не общаются
is Russian honeycombs they are from Yakutia with
то есть руские соты они мо с Якутии с
Varta from Kamchatka and chairs koto from Orel
варты с Камчатки и стулы кото из Орла
where I live here no one even
где я живу здесь никто даже проск не
knows Only the border
знает Это знают только приграничные
villages know this I understood correctly
именно сёла Я правильно понял
that the residents of these border villages
что жители этих приграничных сёл
met with  Ukrainian soldiers Yes, that's what
встречались с украинскими солдатами Да
they said Yes, and what did the
это вот по их словам так было Да а что
Ukrainian soldiers do to them?
украинские Солдаты с ними
They just made a fuss there,
делали ничего они просто они там кипиш
drove in, well, [ __ ],
наводили заезжали там ну
to the store, grandma, give me some bread,
зае в магазин го бабушка Дайте хлеба
bought some bread and left Yes, or what?
купили хлеба и уехали Да или
No, what did they understand? They flew in there,
как Нет что понимали есть залетали там в
how can I explain it, not in themselves, it turns out that
какм объяснить не в сами сла получается
this territory is still there, from the village,
вот эту территорию там же ещ от села
accordingly, yes, that is, there were
соответственно да то есть там были
short firefights, all sorts of such topics,
короткие перестрелки всякая такая тема
wait, firefights, or did people communicate and
подожди перестрелки или люди общались и
listen to these soldiers, I
слушали этих солдат я вам во имею
mean, they will understand the difference, that is, they
вво поймут разницу то есть так же они
also communicated with the soldiers, accordingly,
общались же и с солдатами соответственно
on the soldiers I don't understand that these people personally
на солда Я не понимаю то эти люди лично
saw and heard Ukrainian
видели и слышали украинских
soldiers, I'll explain to you, yes Well, most likely,
солдат я вам объясню да Ну скорее всего
yes Because people tell me so, how
да Потому что люди мне так говори как
most likely You directly said that they
скорее всего Ты прямо сказал что они
heard, you said they were suji, not suji, so
слышали ты сказал они суджи не суджи вот
I'm explaining to you that how would I communicate with
я вам объясняю что как бы я общался с
people, I didn't see them myself, yes, wait I
людьми я их сам не видел да подождите Я
just can't understand the logic somehow, then
просто не могу понять вот как-то логику
these people with whom you communicated, they
то эти люди с которыми вы общались они
communicated with Ukrainians  soldiers or there
общались с украинскими солдатами или там
were some kind of shootouts I can't
какие-то были перестрелки не могу
understand I m I can't explain to you the
понять я м я вам не могу объяснить саму
essence of it, that is, what exactly was
суть то есть что конкретно там
happening there Yes, that is, people I talked
происходило Да то есть люди я общался
to many people too, that is, someone says this,
тоже с многими людьми то есть кто-то так
someone says that, someone says They were
говорит кто-то так кто-то говорит Они
standing there, there was a balaka, there was this and that, you
там стояли там балака там то-сё
know I didn't know I didn't really go into it Well,
понимаете Я я не знал я в это не особо
I just can't understand Here, people all
Ну я просто не могу понять Вот люди все
live in the village Yes, the Ukrainian drug drives
живут в селе Да украинское дрг проезжает
through the border through your border guards
через границу через ваших Пограничников
quietly and calmly arrives in the village and
тихо спокойно приезжает в село и там на
comes to the disco there and says, so now the
дискотеку приходит говорит так сейчас мы
girls and I will dance, we danced and
с девочками потанцуем потанцевали и
went to Velikiy I write and that's it Oh, damn, these are
уехали на Великий пишу и все О блин это
Ukrainians, serve ku, they said or how How did
украинцы послужи ку говорили или как Как
it happen I can't understand I
это происходило не могу понять Я же вам
explained to you what I was saying I wasn't there I do
объяснил что говорю меня там не было я
n't know how it happened Wait, you weren't
не знаю как это происходило подожди тебя
there, but now several times
там не было но теперь несколько раз
maybe once it was I'm ready, you
может один раз было я гото подо ты
say you weren't there, but 2 minutes
говоришь тебя там не было а 2 минуты
ago you told me because the
назад ты мне говорил потому что
Ukrainian military say that the
украинские военные говорят на суж их
locals immediately distinguished themselves, so you said Well,
сразу местные отличились так говорил Ну
yes, I said  everything is correct So uh and
да я говорил всё правильно Так э а
now you say I don't know what you
теперь ты говоришь Не знаю что ты ты
said that the locals talked to the
сказал что местные разговаривали с
Ukrainian military so so so how did the
украинскими военными так так так то как
locals communicate with the Ukrainian military
местные общались с украинскими военными
They came up and treated them to bread I
Они что подходили и хлебом угощали не
can't understand How do I know I'm
могу понять Да я откуда вам знаю я вам
telling you again that I don't know I wasn't there
ещё раз говорю что я не знаю меня там не
That is Well they And weren't you interested in
было То есть Ну они А тебе не интересно
asking the locals How did you say the
было спросить местное Как вы говорили
Ukrainian military didn't take you there I'll
там украинские военные вас не Нели
tell you Well as for me I wasn't
я я вам скажу мне Ну как мне мне было
interested I didn't ask that question exactly Yeah That
неинтересно я такой вопрос именно не
is I wasn't interested
задавал Угу То есть мне было неинтересно
I'm there working and what questions did you
я там работа ка а какие вопросы ты
ask them that they
задавал им что они тебе это
told you that I mean Yes I'm generally saying
рассказали В смысле Да я вообще говорю
how do you live here at all what
как вы тут вообще живёте что у вас тут
happened here And what was the shelling they
происходило Да и что обстреливали
also said What force What force force
говорили тоже Какое сило Какое сило сило
directly it was Kondratovka
непосредственно это было кондратовка
so Kondratovka is Sumy region
так кондратовка - это Сумская область
Ukraine No no And what region
Украина Нет нет А какой области
Kondratovka is Kumy
кондратовка это кумская
region so there is and Kursk region
область так есть и Курская область
Kondratovka
кондратовка
so it is 5 km from the border How did the
так оно 5 км от границы Как это там
Ukrainians come to this force I can't
украинцы приехали в это сило не могу
understand I'll kick the
понять пну
border I don't  ready I don't know Japanese maybe
границу Я не готов я не знаю яп может
it didn't happen Just well people say
этого и не было Просто ну люди говорят
so And maybe not that is you're not sure
так А то может не то есть вы не уверены
that it
что это
happened we
было
see that you saw And you know for sure
видем что вы видели И точно знаете то
why Russia attacked
зачем Россия напала на
Ukraine attacked you think I don't think
Украину напала вы считаете Я не считаю
that it attacked Ukraine Well how don't you
что она напала на Украину Ну как не
think Well usually look a There was Maidan
считаете Ну обычно смотрите а Был Майдан
yes that is they shouted at the Gelika Yes it was
да то есть кричали на гелику Да
right they shouted Putin there
правильно было кричали Путин
was And what happened Well wait about Donbass
было И что было Ну подождите по донбасу
Let's look we were shouting in Kyiv ways
Давайте смотрите мы в Киеве кричали пути
why did you attack by the way Putin they shouted
зачем вы напали кстати Путин кричали уже
after Crimea was seized by Putin
после того как Крым захватил Путин
And you think it was seized yes then
А вы считаете его захваченным да то
why did you They attacked us because we
зачем вы На нас напали из-за того что мы
jumped on the Maidan No no no no I look
на Майдане прыгали Да нене не я смотрите
first of all I'm not the president of this country I ca
во-первых Я не президент этой страны я
n't tell you yes yes Well you How do you
не могу вам да да Ну вы Как вы
support you Support you
поддерживаете вы Поддержи вы
support the attack on Ukraine I'm
поддерживаете нападение на Украину Я
saying how I see it correctly you
говорю как это вижу правильно вы моё
asked my opinion I can't answer you
мнение спросили Я не могу отвечать вам
for the whole country for its president and so
за всю страну за своего президента и так
on I can answer you how I
далее я вам могу ответить то как я это
see it how I think yes yes how you see that's what
вижу как я думаю да да как вы видите вот
Donbass  bombed correctly stop stop stop stop stop
что Донбасс бомбили правильно стоп стоп
How is Donbass it's you They
стоп стоп стоп Как Донбасс это ж вы На
attacked us in what year having captured Crimea
нас напали в чем году захватив Крым
Donetsk Lugansk and it all started then why did
Донецк Луганск и всё началось то зачем
you attack Tell us our troops were
вы напали Рассказывайте наших войск
not there look at the city of Slavyansk you know I
не был смотрите город Славянск знаете я
was there yes on April 12 fourteenth
был там да 12 апреля четырнадцатого года
Russian military led by
российские военные по предводителем
Girkin Yes they entered the city of Slavyansk I was there I was they
гиркина Да зашли в город Славянск я там
still they still they spoke
был я был они ещё они ещё они говорили
not in Donetsk they spoke in Donetsk they say
не по донецки они говорили в Донецке
curb And these Russian military
говорят бордюр А эти российские военные
said curb they told people
говорили поребрик они говорили людям
move behind the curb
отойдите за поребрик
re In Russia they don't say curb either I'll
ре В России тоже не говорят поребрик
say I live in Kharkov My father is
скажу Я живу в Харькове Мой отец родом
from Orel And my mother is from the city of Slavyansk
из Орла А мама родом из города Славянск
they met in Kharkov When we
они в Харькове познакомились Когда
studied and was born there and my
Учились и там родился и у меня бабушка с
grandparents so uh live in the city of Slavyansk
дедушкой так ээ живут в городе Славянск
I was there on the twelfth at their
я был двенадцатого числа у них на день
birthday my grandfather had a
рождения у меня у дедушки было день
birthday on April 12 I remember it just
рождения 12 апреля Я это помню просто
like when these Russian
как вот когда пришли эти российские
militants came Yes they captured the police station
боевики Да захватили отделение полиции
captured the city
захватили гори
took they said that  Mayor Nelya Shtepa she is
взяли сказали что мэра Нелю штепу она
not the mayor now they brought some
теперь не мэр привели какого-то
Ponomarev without teeth he was and they said
понамарёва без зубы такой был и сказали
he will be the mayor now they started to
он теперь будет мэр дальше начали
pull up in the evening from Russia more armored
подтягиваться к вечеру из России ещё
personnel carriers arrived and a landing force approached this one
бтры подъехали да подошла десант этого
from
из
Rostov there was a landing group like there was
Ростова был Десантная группа типа была
Yes we were we were there we were all from the city of
Да мы были мы там были мы все из города
Slavyansk you saw this you talked to these
Славянска это видели вы общались с этими
people soldiers correctly We talked we
людьми солдатами правильно Общались мы
came said Hey what what did you come
приходили говорили Эй что что вы пришли
to us they say look everything now
к нам они говорят смотрите всё сейчас
Calm down now we will hold a
Успокойтесь сейчас мы проведём
referendum like and there will be no military at this
референдум типа и военных на этом не
I was there this is not what
будет Вот я был там это не то что мне
people tell me and my
люди рассказывают и моя бабушка с
grandparents still no one shot
дедушкой до сих не стрелял никто
correctly they shot Yes they shot
правильно стреляли Да застрелили
look yeah well they didn't shoot at me I
смотрите да э ну по мне не стреляли по
know there is one like that in my grandmother's yard
знакомо есть такой вот у бабушки в дворе
lived Sanya Prokhorov Well we with him every
жил Саня Прохоров Ну мы с ним я каждое
summer I came to visit my grandmother yes
лето приезжал бабушке в гости да потому
because my parents took me there to
что меня родители отвозили туда в
Slavyansk and in the next entrance Sanya
Славянск и в соседнем подъезде Саня
Prokhorov lived almost a year apart from mine a
Прохоров жил почти од на год ко мой на
year older eh you can see him Yes
на год старше э его можете посмотреть Да
there is
есть
uh in this in the news yes that in
ээ в этом в новостях было да что в
Slavyansk they shot uh a
Славянске застрелили ээ
man because he took and raised the
мужчину потому что он взял и поднял
Ukrainian flag raised the Ukrainian flag
украинский флаг поднял украинский флаг
there Russians came the Ukrainian flag took down hung up the Russian one he went
там россияне пришли украинский флаг
to
сняли повешали российский он Подошёл к
the city executive committee on this one took took down the
горисполком на вот этой взял снял
Russian flag raised the Ukrainian one came out
Российский флаг поднял украинский вышли
Here they called themselves called
Вот они себя назвали назвали
representatives of the Russian commandant's office
представители российской комендатуры
twisted her
заломали её
arms held like some kind of something
руки провели типа какой-то там что-то
he was taken out to the basement an hour later and on the
его на подвал через час вывели и на
Central Square
Центральной площади
publicly there is a video there is a video there
публично видео есть это есть есть видео
is a video Yes there is a video even Poti was walking around And that's
Да есть видео гуляло даже Поти
it And yes and that's it and they said with everyone who
И всё И да и всё и сказали с каждым кто
Rybnitsa will be like that on the same day a
Рыбница будет так в этот же день начала
lot of people started leaving Slavyansk just
куча народу уезжать из Славянска просто
leaving because they realized that this is already
уезжать потому что поняли что это уже ну
like this is serious At first they thought that this is
типа это серьёзно Сначала думали а это
some kind of just showdown there or
какие-то просто там ну разборки там или
what then in Gorlovka in the neighboring Yes
что всё потом в Горловке в соседней Да
Dmitry Rybak deputy of the Gorlovka
Дмитрий Рыбак депутат горловского
council Russian militants of course
совета российские боевики пуда и
threw him into the river rec everything is official too
выкинули в речку рец всё официально тоже
yes in Donetsk the summer boy Chubenko
есть да в Донецке летнего пацана Чубенко
Look  he himself is from Kramatorsk, he was
Посмотрите он сам родом из Краматорска с
returning from a football match, he is a
футбольного матча возвращался он
football player,
футболист
he is 14 or 15 years old, he
вот 14 Или 15 лет ему у него украинский
had a Ukrainian flag on his backpack,
флажок был на рюкзаке остановили его
Russian soldiers stopped him in Donetsk, in short, everything is
российские военные в Донецке Всё
official, look at
короче официально есть посмотрите это
all this, Yuri, I am just very interested,
всё Юрий Мне просто очень интересно
this is not anywhere because I visit
нигде этого нет потому что я бываю и в
Donetsk and Mariupol, in all these
Донецке и в Мариуполе во всех вот этих
cities in Lugansk, yes, I drove by,
городах в Луганске Да я проезжал я
as I will say, in the World Cup, what is the matter, look, the
как я скажу в ЧМ в чём дело Смотрите
thing is that now, while
дело в том что сейчас пока там
Russian militants are present there, yes, people are
присутствуют российские боевики Да люди
afraid to speak, we had the same thing in Slavyansk on
боятся говорить У нас в Славянске было
July 12, when was it Sanya
тоже самое 12 июля Вот когда ли это Саню
Prokhorov, yes, everyone fell silent, everyone fell silent,
Прохорова Да всё все замолкли все
someone ran away, someone sat down, my
замолкли кто-то убежал кто-то сел мне
grandmother tells me, Andrey, don’t stick your neck out,
бабушка говорит Андрей не высовывайся
just don’t stick your neck out, because she
просто не высовывайся потому что она
knows that I am like this, I have
знает что я такой как бы этот у меня
such a rebellious character, well, I also
характер такой ну бунтарский Я тоже лезу
climb where I am not needed, she says, don’t
сду куда не надо Она говорит не
stick your neck out, and a day later, they
высовывайся всё и через день
took me away so that I could go to
типа вывезли меня чтобы я поехал на
Kharkov to my parents, and there, it turns out, my
Харьков к родителям а там Получается
grandmother lived through the entire occupation,
бабушка прожила всю оккупацию всю
occupation in July when
оккупацию в июле месяце когда боевики
Russian militants had already
российские уже из-за окружения
fled from Slavyansk due to encirclement by Ukrainian troops
украинскими войсками убежали из
then people began to
Славянска тогда люди начали свободно
speak freely And then document all
говорить И тогда документировать все вот
these crimes there was a basement in
эти преступления там Подвал был в
which they took all those
который в которых забирали всех
who disagreed with anything you say against
несогласных любое что скажешь против
Russia for Ukraine everything to the basement to the
России за Украину всё на подвал на
basement in Donetsk there is such a prison
подвал в Донецке есть такая тюрьма
called isolation Look there is a
называется изоляция Посмотрите есть
Ukrainian
украинский
journalist who himself is from
ээ журналист который сам родом из
Donetsk who was arrested there and
Донецка которого там были арестовали и
he sat in this isolation prison How they
он в этой тюрьме изоляции сидел Как там
tortured people there he wrote a whole book
пытали людей он целую книгу написал ели
but they didn’t let him go he was exchanged as
но его не отпустили его обменяли в
part of the exchange even before it
рамках обмена ещё до
started And why exchange such a person who
начала А зачем менять такого человека
knows a lot like that for Russian
который много знает так на российских
soldiers
солдат
they exchanged such a person why not
меняли такого человека почему не
exchange a soldier for a soldier Well that’s how it is
поменять солдата на солдата Ну вот так
because Ukraine said Yes so that
потому что Украина сказала Да чтобы Вот
He needs to be released because well he is a real
его надо выйти потому что ну он реально
media person and then he went and
медийный человек и он потом ездил
told these speeches at the Council of
рассказывал вот эти выступал в Совете
Europe Yes there was a video photo confirmation of his
Европы Да видео фото подтверждение его
words he
слов присутствовало есть есть у него
has a whole documentary book The fact is
есть целая книга документальная Дело в
that the book is what he is yes look In the book
том что кни то что он да смотри В книге
there is an indicator then some of these people
есть и показатель потом часть этих людей
who were workers  this prison and
которые были работниками этой тюрьмы да
then after the liberation of some
потом после освобождения некоторых
territories Yes they were arrested and taken well
территорий Да их арестовали и взяли ну
They gave testimony completely completely
Они давали показания полностью полностью
this is all there is at all not under
это уже всё есть вообще не бы под
Ukraine the
Украиной
territory of the Donetsk region in Slavyansk
территория Донецкой области в Славянске
they were taken Because they went to
их взяли Потому что они ездили в
Slavyansk so and in Slavyansk then
Славянск так вот и в Славянске тогда
them when the part that did not have time to escape
их когда часть которая не успела убежать
Yes they were taken this is all there is already everything And
Да их взяли это всё уже есть всё И
by the way in Slavyansk Yes here is Sanya Prokhorov
кстати в Славянске Да вот Саня Прохоров
yes this is the first to die the first to die at the
да это первый погибший первый погибший
hands of Russian militants the first there is a
от рук российских боевиков первый там
monument to him now in front of the
памятник ему сейчас стоит перед
city council Yes he is like standing like this
городским советом Да он
he holds his hand like this Yes a
такой как бы стоит он так руку держит Да
bronze monument like he
бронзовый такой памятник типа он руку
holds his hand and like he has a bullet Right in the heart That's the one
держит и типа у него пуля Прямо в сердце
on the
Вот такая на
monument like this that every resident of
памятнике вот так что каждый житель
Slavyansk knows and but when there were
Славянска зна и но когда были войска
Russian troops Yes no one my grandmother also didn't
российские Да никто моя бабушка тоже
say anything she had to grandfather
ничего не говорила она приходилось дедом
gave them food because the stores were
им продукты выдавали потому что магазины
closed then because of these military
закрылись тогда из-за этих боевых
actions Yes they gave them food of course
действий Да им продукты выдавали конечно
she doesn't say anything she took these
она ничего не говорит она брала эти
food products to survive yes And she walked quietly
продукты чтобы выжить да И шла тихонько
silent if she was asked there are you for
молчала если её спрашивали там вы за
Ukraine she no no I no because  all those
Украину она нет нет я нет потому что все
who are for Ukraine, they went from apartment to
кто за Украину вот ходили по ээ
apartment looking for, so to speak,
квартирам искали так сказать ээ
Banderovites. Yes, all those who are for Ukraine
бандеровцев Да все кто за Украину
called them Banderovites and threw them in the
называли их бандеровцам и кидали на
basement. My grandmother and grandfather,
подвал вот бабушка моя с дедом они прям
as you can see, they were just like the Leningrad blockade survivors. They
как видишь как блокадники Ленинграда
survived that occupation and
прям вот выжили в этой оккупации и
now Grandma. By the way, she
сейчас Бабушка Она кстати интервью
gave an interview after the liberation of Slavyansk. There
давала после освобождения Славянска вот
is one on the Ukrainian channel and they even showed it on the BBC
есть на украинском канале и по BBC даже
with an English translation.
показывали там с переводом на английский
My grandmother speaks so coolly and this
так прикольно говорит моя бабушка и этот
translator immediately broadcasts it into English.
переводчик как раз сразу на английский
I hear my
транслирует Я слышу как будто мою
grandmother in English. It was so
бабушку на английском языке Это было так
cool. She also told me
прикольно вот и она рассказывала тоже да
how they treated her. How they would have taken the neighbor away.
что как относились Как там соседку
Well, I don’t know this personally. Yes,
отвезли бы ну я не знаю это лично Да
because I didn’t see Sanya Prokhorov.
потому что я это не видел Саню Прохорова
I saw how he was killed and my
Я видел да как его убили а соседку
grandmother told me about the neighbor. She said it directly on the BBC. Yes,
бабушка рассказывал она на BBC прямо
that the
говорила да что
neighbor was killed, too. Well,
соседку и убили типа тоже там ну там в
everyone in the house knows this. I don’t know under
доме все это знают я не знаю как при
what circumstances. Well, in general, the
каких обстоятельствах Ну в общем
Russian military then also because
российские военные тогда тоже потому что
she
она
was there when they said something.
ээ тогда была когда е сказали что-то
Glory to Russia.  she kept silent in response they
слава России она промолчала в ответ к
got to her about something they took her phone and
ней докопались что-то взяли телефон а у
in her phone there were signatures back then
неё в телефоне там были подпис ещё тогда
VKontakte was E is not banned in Ukraine and
ВКонтакте было Э не забанена в Украине и
VKontakte had
ВКонтакте были
groups patriots of Ukraine and so on and so on and in
группы патриоты Украины и так дальше и
short they took her away Well in general there therefore
короче её забрали Ну в общем там поэтому
all this here is not necessary anything you need to
это всё тут не надо ничего нужно
understand that people For example in Russia
понимать что люди Вот например в России
here in Orel people who disagree with the
вот у вас в Орле люди не согласные с
government will come out now To a rally or not in no
власть выйдут сейчас На митинг или нет
way
ни в коем случае
true Wait Why won't they come out
правда Подождите Почему не выйдут Когда
When was the last time you had a rally in Arles
у вас когда у вас в арле был последний
Yes they happen but I'll tell you
митинг Да они бывают но я вам скажу
straight we don't have that many dissenters
прямо у нас нету столько несогласных
there may be someone somewhere well
есть может кто-то где-то ну все в
basically everyone works busy with something nobody The
основном работают чем-то заняты ник не
point is what will happen to a person Yes
Суть в том что будет с человеком Да
who will take and go out in Arles with a
который возьмёт и в арле выйдет с
poster against Putin Yes nothing will
плакатом против Путина Да ничего не
happen I think he will be arrested Yes as in
будет я думаю его арестуют Да как и в
other
других
cities Well now I'll look
городах А ну сейчас сейчас посмотрю
now Let's do it
Сейчас так давай
[music]
[музыка]
I'll just tell you a
Я просто вам
year ago in the role of the Russian Guard officers
год в роле сотрудники росгвардии
detained a local  resident Nikita Solovya
задержали местного жителя Никиту соловья
for a picket against
за пикет против
SVO there is an opportunity to show me this will not
сво есть возможность показать мне это не
work because it is on the screen d the
получится потому что это на экране д
second year The essence in a year still yes and everything you can
второй год Суть в год ещё да и всё можеш
say now I will
сказать сейчас
say
скажу 23
March 23 of the year but look
марта года а вот смотри
Can you tell if you have
Можешь ты сказать если у вас есть
rallies against the government When
митинги против власти Когда у вас в Орле
was the last time you had a rally against the government in Orel and
был последний раз митинг против власти а
I will tell you that with us no matter how it might sound
я вам скажу что у нас как это не звучало
to you I think It is strange that with us
бы для вас я думаю Странно что у нас
90 percent of people are for Putin
процентов 90 начало сво людей за Путина
this is straight 100% Or maybe before the start of SVO
это прям 100% А может до начала сво
maybe you remember some
может вспомните какие-то
rallies Yes there were when there were worked in the
митинги Да были когда были работал в
police In what year I am not ready to
полиции В каком году я вам не готов
tell you I will tell you the battle in the
сказать я вам сеча скажу на
year there were some single pickets Well
году были какие-то одиночные пикеты Ну
there was such a thing in general people stood it was time to
там такое вообще люди постояли пора
disperse there was a show-off people I do not
разошлись там было понты человек я не
know on the square we drove up there in
знаю на площади мы туда подъезжали на
UAZs And you, you worked in the police yes there were
УАЗики А ты ты в полиции работал да
200 people maybe and now you
человек 200 может было а сейчас
work as a policeman no I have not worked for a long time I have
работаешь полицейским не я давно уже не
my own business I am still with  I do
работаю у меня бизнес свой я ещё с
n't work in 2016, that is,
шестнадцатого года не работаю а то есть
So wait, could you remember a rally even
Так подожди ты мог вспомнить митинг ещё
before 2016, that's almost 10 years
до шестнадцатого года это почти 10 лет
ago, yes, yes, I well, I say that's
назад да да да я ну я говорю я так вот
exactly what I remember, we drove up there, like,
именно я помню мы подъехали туда типа
drive up so there's no riots, we drove
подъедьте чтобы не было беспорядков мы
up, stopped, got out of the UAZ and that's it, and
подъехали встали вышли из УАЗика и всё и
stood there, we were on one side, there were
стояли надали мы с одной стороны там
guys on the other side, too, Well, the
ребята ещё с другой приехали тоже Ну
patrols pulled everything together, we stood there, watching,
патрули стянули всё мы стояли смотрели
just so there weren't any mass
просто чтобы не было никаких массовых
fights there, that is, in short, you
Драк там то есть короче после шего года
can't remember any
не можешь вспомнить никакого
rally after last year, I'm honestly telling you what
митинга я нем честно говорю что такое
happened I knew about all this when I worked,
было Я когда работал я об этом всём
just look, also, for example, in
знал просто посмотри также например в
Crimea Yes, they detained girls for
Крыму Да задерживали девушек за
Ukrainian songs, for a Ukrainian flag,
украинские песни за украинский
for a Ukrainian flag I'll never
флажок за украинский флажок Никогда не
believe it, most likely those who were
поверю скорее всего те которые вот были
hanki there were yelling, you were drunk and obogrusya there Well,
ханки там орали вы там обожруся пьяные
it's like it's inherent in the
Ну это как бы присущ да менталитету
Ukrainian mentality, drunk women get drunk and
украинскому женщины пьяные напиваются и
then start fighting near a pub,
там возле пивнухи потом начинают там
yelling there, that is, when sober,
драться кричать там то есть по трезвому
no, they start getting drunk there
нет о нажрутся начинает там бутылками
throw bottles Glory to Ukraine you can shout Well,
кидаться Слава Украине кричать можеш Ну
damn tomorrow you'll oversleep and you'll shout
блин завтра проспишь и будешь кричать
back Well, okay, that's the way it is
обратно ну как бы ладно это ж дело такое
There anyway, there are no people
там ну всё равно не бывает людей
unanimously It's right anyway It just
единогласно правильно всё равно Просто
works out What do you think Well, in
получается Как ты считаешь Ну вот в
Crimea Let's put it this way if a person
Крыму Вот давай так если человек человек
in Crimea, in Chechnya or in Moscow, speaks out
в Крыму в Чечне или в Москве выступит
against Putin or against Kadyrov What will
против Путина или против Кадырова что
he do
ему
again Look how he'll
опять Смотри как он это будет
do it He'll come out with a poster Putin is a
делать выйдет плакатом Путин
thief
вор
First of all, he'll have to somehow
во-первых он это должен будет как-то
back it up That's right I mean,
подкрепить правильно В смысле подкрепить
he wants to back it up He wants to express it's his right Peace
он хочет высказать это его право Мир
Peaceful protest Wait, look, I'll
Мирный протест Подождите ну смотрите
explain
объясню
Valo That's not
Вало этоже нет этоже
right That's wrong But if one insults another, do
неправа Но если один другого оскорбляет
you think it's acceptable Well, why, for
вы считаете это приемлемо Ну почему
example, in Germany can they? Why in the USA,
например в Германии могут там шоль в США
Trump is a thief on Mitin, they have same-sex marriages
Трамп вор на Митин у них однополые браки
Well, just like you I'm glad
Ну как и у вас Рад
about In Russia, in Russia, you can't say Putin is a thief
про в России в России сказать Путин вор
Listen, even I wouldn't like it I'll
нельзя послушайте даже мне бы это не
tell you That is, someone from the locals
скажу то есть кто-то бы из местных точно
would definitely have fired at the cuckoo That is, if
бы в кукушку зарядил бы то есть е если
you saw that a person  standing with a poster
ты видел что человек стоит с плакатом
Putin is a thief you should hit him in the head yes maybe
Путин вор ты бы его в голову да возможно
Yes I wonder but you as a former
Да интересно а вот ты как бывший
police officer how do you rate how you are
полицейский как оцениваешь как ты
classified with a poster this is an
квалифицируется с плакатом это
offense Of course I agree with this
правонарушение Конечно я согласен с этим
Yes I paid a 500 ruble fine for this in the
Да Я заплатил 500 руб штрафа за это в
sense of 500 rubles this is hooliganism already this is
смысле 500 руб это хулиганство уже это
not 500
не 500
rubles even no this is petty hooliganism
руб даже нет это мелкое хулиганство
understand that a
повни что
person I have something to confirm
человеко я с те есть чем подтвердить
these words What No questions but if
данные слова Что Вопросов нет но если
you have nothing to confirm this head
тебе нечем подтвердить это голов
fu judicial
фу судебной
system judicial system I would simply express
сист судебной систе Просто я бы выразил
my dissatisfaction to him too
ему тоже своё
expresses dissatisfaction I
недовольство выражает недовольство я
expressed Yes but he is in a peaceful way And you
выразил Да но он в Мирный способ А ты
in his
ему в
face Peaceful way and slander of a person I
табло Мирный способ а клевета человека я
would not say that
бы не сказал что
peace and slander do not look if this
мир а клевета не смотри если этот
person yes thinks Yes that this is slander he will
человек да считает Да что это клевета он
file
подат
then he will file a lawsuit and the court then decides
тогда он подат в суд и суд тогда решает
Let a passerby not decide slander or not
Дай прохожий не решае клевета или не
slander do not wait I would ask him a
клевета не подождите я бы ему задал
question On what basis are you standing here at all
вопрос На основании чего вообще ты здесь
and firstly with this on the basis of the
стоишь и во-первых с этим на основании
Constitution which  allows yes peaceful
Конституции которая разрешает да мирные
assemblies Your Constitution allows
собрания У вас же Конституция разрешает
peaceful
мирные
assemblies sos atno ruto
собрания сосен атно
onov
руто
is the same Civilian
онов такой же Гражданский
and in the Constitution it is somehow stated that
а в Конституции есть как-то что
civilians have the right to
гражданские люди имеют право
restrict the rights of other
ограничивать права других гражданских
civilians to peaceful assemblies I told you
людей на мирные собрания Я же вам сказал
I would pay a fine for this I understand everything is
Я бы заплатил за это штраф понял всё
fine the question is I would break the law for
хорошо вопрос е я бы нарушил закон за
this pay a fine if a person stood
это заплатил штраф если бы человек стоял
with a poster that in Russia or in the city of
с плакатом что вот в России или в городе
Orel you stood with a poster Crimea is
Орёл у тебя стоял с плакатом Крым - это
Ukraine what would
Украина чтоб с ним
happen to him What would happen to him
было Чтоб с ним
Well the question is who would have caught him
было Ну вопрос того кому бы Он попался
Let's e I tell you adequately and honestly
Давайте е я вам адекватно и честно
yes The question is who would have
говорю да Вопрос того кому бы Он
caught him that's all Well what would have happened
попался вот и всё Ну то что что бы было
to
с
him Well I
ним Ну я
think something good would have happened well for
думаю хорошего врат что-то бы было ну к
example what would have happened If the police had
примеру что бы было Вот если полиция
driven up to him or what happened the
подъехала к нему или что что случилось
authorities did
органы власти
not do that is authorities such
не сделали то есть органы власти такие
as the police
как полиция ничего
would have nothing the deputy and sent him home or stood there for 2-3
бы зам и ул домой или стоял бы там 2-3
days I don't know Well I think most likely there would have been
дня Я не знаю Ну я думаю скорее всего бы
Activists people who
Нашлись бы активисты люди просто которые
were just talking to him
были с ним
no longer for 500 rubles
беседу уже не на 500 руб
more expensive  Regional
подороже
Committee Crimea with
Обком Крым с
Russia broke
Россия слом
Crimea is
Крым это
Ukraine I think the same thing about That is, you
Украина Я думаю тоже самое о То есть ты
say that you talked with someone there
говори что ты там с кем-то говорил
talked Now do you really
говорил говорил Теперь ты реально
understand that a person who in Crimea in
понимаешь что человек который в Крыму в
Donetsk in Lugansk in
Донецке в Луганске на оккупированных
these occupied territories will come out with a poster that
этих территориях выйдет с плакатом что
he is for Ukraine
он за Украину
Yes, he will express the Ukrainian
Да будет высказывать про украинскую
position,
позицию
either certain Russian activists will
либо определённые российские активист
kick him Yes, and they will take him to the basement or the
ноги Да и заберут на подвал либо это
FSB will do it wait, I'm not talking about
сделает ФСБ стойте подождите я не говорю
anyone about the basement, no
никого про подвал про подвала никаких
activists are obliged
активистов
that they survived, the same thing in
обя что пережили то те же самое в
Donetsk, people survived shelling,
Донецке люди переживали обстрелы у
someone's relatives died at the hands of the Ukrainian army, that's what
кого-то от рук украинской армии погибли
I understand correctly Yes,
родственники вот я правильно понимаю Да
what in Crimea, look if we
что в Крыму смотрите если мы сейчас
come now and ask people in Crimea
приедем и у людей будем в Крыму
or will they ask Do you agree that
спрашивать или они у Вы согласны что
people will be afraid to answer That they are for
люди будут бояться отвечать Что они за
Ukraine, really, I absolutely
Украину правда абсолютно не
disagree Let's do it again, I'm
согласен Давайте ещё раз ещ раз
not confused Look, I'm confused Let's do it
не запутался Смотри я запутался Давайте
again, let's do it like this a person who is in Crimea
раз давайте так человек который в Крыму
for Ukraine He can come out and say that
за Украину Он может выйти и сказать что
he is for Ukraine, you can listen to me,
он за Украину можете меня заслушать
let's ask a
давай задали
question, hand over  question then cut it somehow
вопрос сдали вопрос потом рез его как-то
go on What will people be afraid of in Crimea
пону пере Что будут люди бояться в Крыму
And you will open Crimea Ukraine when was the
А вы откроете Крым Украина когда был
photo video Look and look
фотографии видео Посмотрите и посмотрите
now and How do you think what will people
сейчас и Как вы считаете что вам люди
tell you they want Ukraine again Look I'm
скажут они хотят опять Украину Смотри я
just asking do you agree that a person
просто спрашиваю ты согласен что человек
who is now in Crimea will say that Crimea
который сейчас в Крыму скажет что Крым -
is Ukraine or that he is for Ukraine it will
это Украина или что он за Украину ему
be very painful for him
будет очень больно
yes maybe no maybe he will not come across
да может и нет может ему не попадётся
anyone you understand but
никто понимаете но
Yes now look those same people
Да теперь смотри те самые ные люди
who were born there I will tell you no yes
которые там же родились я вам скажу не
yes look if people in Crimea understand that
да да смотри если люди в Крыму понимает
saying that they are for Ukraine is
что сказать что они за Украину это
dangerous then will you a person who
опасно то будут ли вам человеку который
comes from Russia be aggressively
приезжает из России агрессивно такому
inclined to say that they are for Ukraine I am
настроено говорить что они за Украину я
not aggressively inclined against
не настроен агрессивно не против
anyone Well they understand they understand that
кого Ну они же понимают они понимают что
you will be Well how Not aggressively against
вы будете Ну как Не агрессивно против
whom did you want a scoreboard just because he is
кого ты хотел табло просто за то что он
standing with a poster Putin is a thief and you Not
с плакатом Путин вор стоит и ты Не
aggressively inclined and here people say
агрессивно настроены а тут люди говорят
that they are for Ukraine you understand one
что они за Украину вы поймите одну
difference here here is a difference he
разницу здесь здесь разница он один
insults a person unreasonably and the
оскорбляет человека необоснованно а
other simply expresses his opinion
другой просто высказывает своё мнение
this is also a difference I understood everything  Let's
это же тоже разница всё понял Давай так
clarify so that I understand correctly
значит уточним чтобы я правильно понял
if in Orel you see a person with a
если в Орле ты увидишь человека с
poster Putin is a thief you are his sign yes it's a
плакатом Путин вор ты ему табло да это
su Yes and if in Orel you see a person
су Да а если ты в Орле увидишь человека
with a poster Crimea is Ukraine What will you
с плакатом Крым - это Украина Что ты
do to
сделаешь
him you know I wouldn't
ему знаете я ничего бы е не
do anything well someone else Will do yes
сделал ну кто-то другой Сделает да
why I think it's unlikely And what's the point
почему я думаю вряд ли А зачем смысл
stop well the person thinks so 4 minutes ago
стоп ну человек так счита 4 минуты назад
you said that with him Oh they will do even
ты рассказывал что с ним Ох сделают ещё
worse when I said this You are a raska
круче когда я это сказал Ты же раска
so Look look I told you
так Смотрите смотрите я Я же вам сказал
I am personally speaking my opinion is correct I
Я говорю лично своё мнение правильно я
cannot speak for society for the
не могу говорить за общество за
president and so on I told you this too
президента и так далее я вам тоже это
correctly maybe they will be found
сказал правильно вот возможно найдутся
maybe not I
возможно нет я
assumed that's all Yeah that is for
предположил вот и всё Угу то есть Ради
God's sake let him think so but the fact
Бога пусть он так думает но факт
remains a fact correct that is we in
остаётся фактом правильно то есть мы в
Russia can go to Crimea and we all
России можем ехать в Крым и мы все
understand and you understand kr Let's cut the
понимаем и вы понимаете кры Давай подрез
people who live in Crimea it is dangerous for them to
люди которые живут в Крыму им опасно
say that they are for Ukraine it is not dangerous and
сказать что они за Украину не опасно и
nothing Why Why did you decide that well
ничего Почему С чего вы так взяли ну
because for them for them for them at least
потому что им им им им как минимум
aggressive Russians sign why
агрессивные россияне табло почему
Russians Well, well, well, wait Yes, in
россияне Ну ну а ну подождите Да в
principle, you are right because Crimea is
принципе Вы правы потому что Крым - это
Russia and now there are also Russians there,
Россия и там теперь тоже россияне
right, accordingly, the same people
правильно соответственно те же люди
who
которые
support it, I agree that
поддерживают согласен что
these
эти
years are Crimea, why is it a third time, let's
годи рым приче норо третий раз давайте
either take turns Yes, let's take turns, it's my
либо по очереди Да давай по очереди моя
turn, my turn Look,
очередь моя очередь Смотри
Crimea, a lot of Russians have arrived,
кры Крым приехало очень много россиян
really Why are you talking so disrespectfully, you're
правда Почему вы без уважение так
interrupting me,
разговариваете это ты меня перебиваешь
you
ты
respect me, look,
уважает смотри
let's ask your question, look,
давай задашь свой вопрос смотри в Крым
a lot of Russians have arrived in Crimea after the
приехало Много россиян после
occupation What does it mean to rest, to
оккупации приехала Что значит отдыхать
live, what is not to live, to live
жить что нет жить
I think yes, yes And why not So
жить Я думаю да да А почему нет Так
now the people who lived in Crimea before the
теперь люди которые жили в Крыму до
occupation, they are worried that for their
оккупации они Переживают что за ихние
statements that they are for Ukraine, these
высказывания что они за Украину вот эти
Russians who have come here, they can do
понаехавшие россияне им могут сделать
very bad things to them or the FSB can
очень плохо или ФСБ их
send them away I think no I think you are
отправить Я думаю нет Я думаю вы
talking nonsense, you are somehow
глупости говорите вы ну как-то очень
reacting very strangely to everything, the occupation, the occupation
странно на всё реагируете оккупация
came, built roads,
оккупация пришла построила дороги
kindergartens, schools, the occupation does not
детские сады школы оккупация этого не
do this, built a bridge Everything completely,
делает построила мост Всё полностью
when Ukraine, even when Mariupol
когда Украина ещё даже когда Мариуполь
was Ukrainian, blocked the water there
был украинский перекрыла туда воду
for some reason it's your people you
зачем-то это же ваши люди правильно вы
think right interrupt me again Because
считаете ме опять перебивайте Потому что
you talk for a long time I got it I immediately
ты долго говоришь я понял я сразу
argument argument you say that during
аргумент аргумент ты говоришь что в
the occupation they don't build schools look under the
оккупации не строят школы смотри при
Germans Look No I immediately Let me
немцах Посмотри Нет я я сразу Давай я
immediately parry yours Yes because
тебе сразу с парируй твою Да потому что
you talk a lot I immediately to you Look
ты много говоришь я сразу тебе Смотри во
during the German occupation the Germans built
время оккупации немецкой немцы строили
roads built bridges built schools
дороги строили мосты строили школы
built universities even yes why are you
строили университеты даже да почему вы
interrupting me because I don't
перебивает меня потому что я не
interrupt I immediately answered you see
перебиваю я сразу ответил тебе видишь
come on
давай
[music] You
[музыка]
see how you communicate that's why you're going to run
Вот видите как вы общаетесь поэтому вас
away now you're getting ready to run away I
ты сейчас убежишь ты готовишься убежать
already know people like you when I'm cleaning you up based on
Я таких как ты знаю уже когда тебя по
facts Yes you immediately start
фактам прибираю Да ты сразу начинаешь
shouting that you're being interrupted and run away
кричать что тебя перебивают и убегайте
Come on And then then we'll continue the
Давай И тогда тогда мы дальше продолжим
constructive dialogue constructive the
конструктивный диалог конструктивный
Germans built roads What are you saying the
немцы строили дороги Что вы говорите
Germans built roads during the occupation
немцы во время оккупации строили
during where they built
дороги во время како где они строили
roads already in the plenum they built roads No no
дороги уже пле нем строили дороги Нет
no during the Nazi  occupation of the
нет нет во время гитлеровской оккупации
same Crimea they built roads there
того же Крыма там строили дороги
shops theaters everything
магазины театры всё
worked what are you talking about yeah Where were the Germans
работало что вы несёте да Где немцы во
during the war And what year in what year were they
время войны А какой год в каком году они
from forty-first to forty-four Are you
с сорок первого по сорок четвёртый Вы
kidding Look Why
что прикалываетесь Посмотрите Поче по
forty-four
сорок четвёртый
Yes wait And in what year was Crimea
Да подождите А в каком году Крым был
liberated from the occupiers How how
освобождён от оккупантов Как как они в
could they build anything there at all
со чем могли вообще там что-то строить
if there hadn't been anything there for a long time what are you
если там уже не было давно что вы
Tell me Did you have a better
Рассказывайте У вас был лучше урок
history lesson at school Come on So look
истории школе по Давай Так посмотри в
what year Crimea was
каком году Крым
liberated I can't now I'm
освободили Я сейчас не могу меня сейчас
not with the guard right now I have a computer in another
не с поруч У меня компьютер в другой
room I'm talking to the phone Now we'll
комнате я с телефоном говорю Сейчас
see
посмотрим
you just now we started at the same time you now
тебе просто мы сейчас начали заодно вы
about the war Why now
сейчас вот про войну Зачем Сейчас
distance yourself I'm telling you Right now at the
отдаляться я вам говорю Сейчас в данный
moment Crimea was liberated uh May 12
момент вот Крым освободили ээ 12 мая
forty-four from the Germans I was
сорок четвёртого года от немцев Я был
right and you obviously didn't study history at school
прав а ты в школе историю не учил видно
again I looked I can't
ещё раз я посмотрел я се не могу
check I don't want you the offensive
проверить не хочу вами наступательная
operation was carried out from April 8 to
операция проводилась с 8 апреля по 12
May 12 forty-something year why did they do
мая сорок чего года соче го там делали
this there  they built roads so look
это строили дороги так вот смотри Во
During the occupation yes the Germans for the management of
время оккупации да немцы для управления
these territories also built in all the
этими территориями также строили на всех
occupied territories when the Germans
оккупированных территориях когда немцы
occupied France there they built the Armed Forces
оккупировали Францию там строили ВС
also built
строилось также и
Russia this is specifically for logistics Yes I
Россия это чтобы именно для логистики Да
believe somewhere Maybe they have some kind of
я поверю где-то Может они там какой-то
pontoon bridge there a crossing Yes but they did
Понтонный мост там переправу Да но нигде
not lay any asphalt anywhere there they did
там не клали никакой асфальт ничего они
not build anything there to build - this means
там не строили строить - это значит
thoroughly and the fact that they there if
основательно а то что они там если
some crossing is corrected I do not
какую-то переправу подправить Я не
think that this is some kind of grandiose
считаю что это какая-то грандиозная
construction and here now in Crimea
Стройка а здесь сейчас в Крыму
Look there they built Tavrida a whole
Посмотрите там построили Таврида целую
highway between through the whole of Crimea they have
магистраль между через весь Крым уже
almost finished building a road And on this side of the
почти достроили дорогу А с этой стороны
Sea of ​​Azov that's right super super
Азовского моря правильно супер супер
You say Look And you say that Crimea
Говорите Смотрите А вы говорите что Крым
means Ukraine And what why then the
значит это Украина А что почему тогда
Ukrainian government with its own Ukrainian as it
власть Украины своим же украинцем как
believed cut off the water they simply
она считала отрезала воду просто канал
blocked the channel and everything to the people as to the people who
перекрыли и всё людям как людям которые
whole I explain I
целый объясняю
explain correctly they poured
объясняю правильно перели
water I explain
воду объясняю потому
because the holding of the occupied territories
что удержание оккупированных территорий
according to the statute it lies on the occupier perch
по статута он лежит на окун оккупант
should yes Russia started the military Zro
должен да Россия начала милитари Зро
Crimea to bring in different troops to build
Крым заводить туда разные войска делать
bases from which then Ukraine attacked Kherson
базы с которых потом напала на Херсон
Yes Ukraine did the right thing by
Украина Да Украина правильно делала что
cutting off the military infrastructure of Crimea This is
отрезала военную инфраструктуру Крыма
because
Вот это потому что на обеспечение этой э
the same water and
инфраструктуры шла та же вода
electricity were used to provide this infrastructure Absolutely right But these are
электроэнергия Абсолютно верно но Это
all small details the point is not that The point is that
всё мелочи суть не в том Суть в том что
Russia captured what it is building there and so
Россия захватила что она там строит и
on this should not interest anyone at all
так дальше это вообще никого не должно
if for example yes Ukraine uh
интересовать если например да Украина ээ
took it to court and built a store it became
в суд же взяла и построила магазин стала
Ukrainian because of this this territory no
от этого эта территория украинская нет
because Russia is
от того что Россия на оккупированных
building something in the occupied territories because of this the
территориях что-то строит от этого
territories do not cease to be
территории не перестают быть
occupied if I come to your
оккупированы если я приду завтра в вашу
apartment tomorrow and do repairs in it because of
квартиру да и сделаю в ней ремонт от
this the apartment will not become mine if I
этого квартира не станет моя если я
come to your car tomorrow
завтра приду в вашу машину
Yes I will wash it uh I will
Да помою
wash it I will fill it up I will drive it for
её уу её помою буду её заправлять
10 years Yes
Кататься буду 10 лет на ней кататься Да
fill it up with gas do repairs
заправлять её бензином проводить ремонт
will it become my car because of this Stolen it will
станет ли от этого это моя машина
not become true
Украденная не станет правда так
No matter if I stole this thing
Независимо если я украл эту вещь
no matter how much I invest in it
независимо от того сколько я в неё
how I look at it there it is not  it
вкладываю как я за неё там смотрю она не
becomes mine it is stolen just like that no matter
стаёт моей она украдена так же так
how much money Russia is pouring
сколько бы Россия не вливаю сейчас денег
into this territory now and it is pouring
в эту территорию а она вливает потому
because it is infrastructure as if it is
что это инфраструктура как бы это
military there plus it is necessary to show that no matter how
военная там плюс надо показать что как
all this does not become its territory does not
бы всё это не стаёт её территория не
become And that's all And the most important thing from which you are
стаёт И всё И самое главное от чего ты
running away is the question yes about the fact that people
убегаешь вопроса да о том что люди
who will speak you say there they say people who go out
которые будут выступать ты говоришь там
in
там говорят люди которые в
Crimea sing a Ukrainian song they are
Крыму выходят песню украинскую поют их
arrested they are fined people who
арестовывают штрафуют люди которые
went out in embroidered shirts on
выходили в вышиванки на День
Independence Day of Ukraine they were fined people
независимости Украины их штрафовали люди
who say that they are for Ukraine their are
которые говорят что они за Украину их
come on now watch the news stop
аре давай вот сейчас смот новости стоп
look come on
смотри
Shut up and we are now those zata you
давайс Закрой рот и мы сейчас те зата ты
said
сказал
nonsense Look come on so in the
бред Вот смотри давай так в
occupied Yalta security forces detained a
оккупированной ял силовики задержали
resident of Yalta Aishe Asro for
жительницу Ялты Айше асро за
statements in Ukrainian egam groups
высказывания в украинских egam группах
so employees with in Yalta
так сотрудники с в Ялте
detained a man detained for Ukrainian
задержали задержан мужчина за украинскую
symbols That's just Yalta I took
символику Вот это только Ялту я взял
Let's take it even further look so
Давай ещё дальше возьмём смотри так
Crimea se you can read this endlessly
Крыму се можете читать это бесконечно у
you write there you have there  There are a lot of Chukovs, they are
вас там пишут у вас там Чуков много они
not me there. I am with No, I take Russian ones and there are
там не я Я с Нет я российские беру и там
photos and videos
фото ж видео есть нене не так вот
there. No, no, that's how they detained 55 Ukrainian citizens in Crimea and in the Kherson region. So, in Crimea, Russian security forces detained a summer resident of the city for allegedly cooperating with Ukrainian intelligence. So, in Simferopol, they detained a man for the Ukrainian flag. A Crimean Tatar was detained in Crimea for Ukrainian symbols. This is fake information. You can't have such
фейковая информация у вас такой не может
information. Well, there really is a last
быть информации Ну вот Ну реально есть
name. Look, this is all being checked.
есть фамилия Смотри это всё проверяется
This is all being checked. Well, you agree. Yes,
это ж всё проверяется Ну ты согласись
you understand, yes, as a former
Да ты ж понимаешь да ты как бывший
Russian police officer, you understand that
полицейский России ты ты понимаешь что у
you are doing what you are
вас
doing with people who generally oppose the government. And with people
выступают что делают Да а с людьми
who are in the occupied territories, you
которые на оккупированных территориях ты
also understand what to do, so there is no
тоже понимаешь что делать поэтому не
need to build some kind of nonsense.
надо строить се какую-то ерунду
I just traveled to all the new
горо Я ездил просто по всем вот новым
regions, I am with many people. That's right.
регионам я с людьми с многими правильно
I'm telling you, you can communicate with
я тебе говорю ты можешь общаться с кем
anyone, but no one will tell
угодно но никто тебе не скажет что во
you what. Enough, let's ask.  Skat What's
Хватит вам вопрос давай Скат А что
wrong with me I'm an ordinary citizen of a good country
такого я обычный гражданин хорошо страны
Let's do it this way if you're an ordinary citizen Yes, they'll
Давай так если ты обычный гражданин Да
take you on a tour of the prison And
тебя на экскурсию в тюрьму приведут Да и
you'll ask the prisoners Does the
ты у заключённых спросишь
prison warden treat you well Someone will say that it's
тюрьмы кто-то скажет что
bad Listen, everyone has their own opinion
плохо послушайте у каждого сво мнение
Of course I've met many people I've been to many places I've
Конечно я я встречал много где бывал я
talked to a lot Let's do it
разговаривал давай так
this way Someone from the prison will tell you that in public
заклю вот так скажет тебе что публично
Yes, in front of the prison warden Yes, that the
Да при начальники тюрьмы Да что
prison warden treats us badly
начальник тюрьмы плохо к нам
Why not he won't say
относится вполне Почему нет не скажет
Because you'll leave And it
ска Потому что ты уйдёшь А ему
will be the same for him And here you came a
будет так само также и тут ты приехал
Russian from Orel an occupier came to
россиянин из Орла оккупант приехал в
Crimea Do they really understand or something They'll
Крым Они тко понимают чтоли они что-то
say something against Russia Tomorrow they'll be
скажут против России Завтра они будут
interrogated by the
как минимум на допросе
FSB at the very least with the subsequent consequences
ФСБ с последующими последствиями
It's all just nonsense, not nonsense And as
всё просто глупости не глупости А по
for whose Crimea is I'll also give you an
поводу того чей Крым я вам тоже приведу
example Let's say you're
пример давай вот вы
married Married no no no Well, there you are Well, there were
женаты женаты нет нет нет ну вот Ну были
no Imagine, you have a wife
нет представить можете вот у вас жена
Well, let's say a girl Let's say There's a
есть Ну девушка допустим Пусть Там
girl who
девушка
tells you there conditionally there
да говорит вам там условно там
Peter you mean you don't buy me
Пётр ты мне значит ла не покупаешь на
nails no
ногти не
you don't fulfill your marital
даёшь не исполняешь свой супружеский
duty as you should but only I earn money yes
долг как надо а только Я зарабатываю да
We work together only I have tamr navo
Мы вместе работаем толь у меня тамр наво
nazh
наж
[music] I
[музыка]
like Sergey he is
мне вот Сергей нравится он мне и платье
going to buy me a dress and that and you mean and I'm
будет покупать и то и вы значит и я
leaving for Sergey And you say No you won't
ухожу к Сергею А вы говорите Нет не
leave She says No no I'm leaving for
уйдёшь Она говорит Да нет я ухожу к
Sergey I have already filed for
Сергею Я уже подала на
divorce I am with you
развод я с вами
[music]
[музыка]
[applause] we
[аплодисменты]
said goodbye on the head and Peter now
распрощались по башке и Пётр теперь
runs around there gathering friends there in Europe
бегает там друзей собирает там по Европе
where he can and can do nothing
где может и ничего сделать не может
because he understands understood You had such a
потому что он понимает понял У вас такая
situation with your wife yes I understand
ситуация с женой была да я так понимаю
you Peter in this scheme or Sergey No
вы Пётр в этой схеме или Сергей Нет у
I didn't have such I just gave you an
меня не было такого Я просто вам привёл
example How you gave me an example of the beginning of
пример Как вы мне привели пример нач
that now look Now look And
того те теперь смотри Теперь смотрите А
now I'll explain to you How it works
теперь я я вам объясню Как это работает
in the state if some person for
в государства если какой-то человек
example some bearded man from the Oryol
например какой-то бородатый из орло
region wants to live in Germany he goes
области да хочет жить в Германии он едет
to Germany yeah yeah so because you don't have it
в Германию угу так от того что нет у вас
in Oryol  regions If you want to go to
в Орловской области Если ты захочешь в
Germany, here are people from the Oryol region who
Германию вот люди из Орловской области
moved to Germany, many of them Yes, he
переезжали в Германию много таких Да
moved to live, they wanted to live there because
переехал жить они захотели туда жить от
they want to live in Germany, it doesn’t
того что они хотят жить в Германии не
mean that Germany should take the
значит что Германия должна забрать себе
Oryol region for itself, really, so if
орловскую область правда так вот если
there is a person in Crimea who
есть какой-то человек в Крыму который
wants to live in Russia, he takes a
хочет жить в России он берёт садится на
train and goes to Russia and
поезд и едет в Россию и там
lives there, if a person from Krasnodar wants to
живёт если человек из Краснодара хочет
live in Belarus, he gets on a train and
жить в Беларуси Он садится на поезд и
goes there and lives there Yes, yeah, the territory of
едет туда и там живёт да Угу территория
Ukraine is the territory of the state of
Украины - это территория государства
Ukraine, it is the territory of all residents of
Украина это территория всех жителей
Ukraine, the city where I live,
Украины город в котором я живу
Khmelnitsky, is the territory of all citizens of
Хмельницкий это территория всех граждан
Ukraine, the city of Simferopol, don’t
Украины город Симферополь го не
interrupt You see, you’re interrupting me, the city of
перебивай Видишь ты меня перебиваешь
Simferopol, the city of Simferopol, the center,
город Симферополь город Симферополь цент
is the territory of all citizens of Ukraine Yes, not just
это территория всех граждан Украины Да
anyone Who wanted to go there, is it
ни кого-то одного Кто там захотел там
to Russia or not, that’s all Who wants to go to
это в Россию или нет это всё Кто хочет в
Russia,
Россию
please, in Russia we agree, and the
пожалуйста в России мы согласны а
territory of Ukraine is a single and
территория Украины - это единая и
indivisible territory of all citizens of
неделимая территория всех граждан
Ukraine, that’s why these fables of yours, yes And
Украины поэтому твои вот эти басни да А
you’re just an ordinary Russian cop
ты просто обычный российский мент
who threw people into plots And yes,
который и людей участки И
that’s for you  everything is clear
и подкидывал да по тебе это всё понятно
Yes you would to the person
Да ты бы человеку
who is standing with the poster you would And you know
который стоит с плакатом ты бы А знаешь
why you know why you to the person who is
почему знаешь почему ты человеку который
standing with the poster Putin is a thief Well why
стоит с плакатом Путин вор Ну почему
Because you understand that
Потому что ты понимаешь что
you You understand that you serve your
ты Ты понимаешь что ты служишь своему
master and you do not have the courage to tell him anything
хозяину да и у тебя нет духа ему что-то
And when you see a person
сказать И когда ты видишь человека
who dares to tell this system
который осмеливается этой системе
that Putin is a thief is not afraid For you
сказать что Путин вор не боится Для тебя
he is with you you are not you do not have hatred for
он при ты ты не у тебя нет ненависти на
those oligarchs who rob you you do
тех олигархов которые тебя грабят у тебя
not have hatred for those officials who
нет ненависти на тех чиновников которые
paid you a meager salary Yes that's it But
тебе мизерную зарплату платили Да вот Но
you have Hatred for the person who
у тебя есть Ненависть к человеку который
dared to say that he is not a slave that he
осмелился сказать что он не раб что он
can say that Putin is a thief for him
может сказать что Путин вор для него
Putin is not a king and all this infuriates you
Путин не царь и всё это тебя бесит
because slaves are slaves they are the most Yes they do
потому что рабы рабы они больше всего Да
not like those who are
не любят тех кто
free they are ready to kiss their master
свободен они своего хозяина готовы
And they despise the person who will say that
целовать А человека который скажет что
he is not a slave because
он не раб они презирают потому что
you understand your VS
свободного человека ты понимаешь сво ВС
when all around are slaves you are like that Well yes But
когда вокруг все рабы ты такой Ну да Но
they are all slaves all And when around people
это все рабы все А когда вокруг люди
who say I am not a slave It is difficult for you
которые говорят я не раб Тебе сложно
to remain half difficult for you to understand You
оставаться полу сложно тебе понять Ты
true I have my own business I
правда я у меня свой бизнес я Хорошо
earn well I am not offended this country I am
зарабатываю я не обижен эту страну я
proud and glad that I am not alive pony
горд и ра что я в неживу понино
le and my president you know He raised
ле и Мой президент понимаешь Он поднял
the country from its knees from its knees you know
страну с колен с колен понимаешь
yes that's why I owe him you know that's
да поэтому я ему обязан обязан понимаешь
why I will support him Now 90% for the sake of
поэтому его поддержит Сейчас 90% ради
interest for the sake of interest what did your
интереса ради интереса что сделал твой
president do how he raised What happened
президент как он поднял Что случилось
What did he do for Well I'll explain after the
Что он сделал для Ну объясню после
collapse of the Soviet Union the country you can't
развала Советского Союза страна этого не
hide it it was like that 2000 Putin
скрыть она была так вот 2000 год Путин
came what what he changed what he changed
пришёл что что он изменил что он изменил
what he did yes it turns into a farce
что сделал да превращается в балаган
used to chat chat It's just that I know
привыкли болтать болтать Просто я знаю
that Putin raised the retirement age it
что Путин поднял пенсионный возраст она
became richer the retirement age is higher how did it
стала богаче пенсионный возраст выше как
happen Usually I'll tell you now
так получилось Обычно я вот сейчас тебе
Just let's take turns not like that I'll
расскажу Только давай по очереди не так
throw it all out later you know well
что это всё выкину потом понимаешь ну
let's sort it out
давай разбирать
also raised with Kolya then when
ещё вот поднял с Коле тогда когда был
Yeltsin was when ships were
Ельцин когда корабли в девяностые года
cut up for scrap metal in the nineties when bases were
резали на металлолом когда базы
falling apart salaries were not paid
разваливались не платили зарплатам
cowsheds all this was falling apart yes there
коровники всё это разваливалось да не
was nothing of our own bought Bush's legs the
было ничего своего закупали ножки Буша
so-called Duma So that  here I
так называемые Дума Так что зде Всё я
understood everything under Yeltsin was What did
понял при ельцине была Что сделал
Putin listen yes So tell me what Putin
Путин послушай да Так скажи что Путин
did Listen Economy time Come on or
сделал Послушай Эконом время Давай или
not or Tell me what Putin
не или Рассказывай что Путин
did burned burned you see
сделал подгорел подгорел видишь потому
because you can't say anything you
что ты не можешь ничего сказать ты не
can't say what you did For you pu
можешь сказать что сделал Для тебя пу
say
говори
Tell me what Putin did that Yeltsin
Скажи что сделал Путин то что Ельцин
did nothing and did bad things I know
ничего не делал и делал плохое я знаю
everything tell me what
всё расскажи что сделал
Putin did with your tongue you can't see everything Come on get out
Путин языком не всё видишь Давай идёшь
of here that's all that's all the quintessence of
отсюда вот и всё вот и всё квинтесс
this conversation that if I saw a
этого разговора что если бы я увидел
man with a poster Putin is a thief I would give him a
человека с плакатом Путин вор Я б ему
face for 500 rubles that's
лицо за 500 руб вот и
all a good conversation Poli of this type like a squeak a
всё хороший разговор был Поли этого типа
comment for Sanya
лайк писка комент за Саню
Prokhorov a letter to y Telegram right now
Прохорова пись на й Telegram прям зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube is busy with
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through SRG OR in your ban and very
нас через срг ор в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show people at times I don't
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so that
показуе информация про стримы тому для
we Mali is operational  links are
того щоб мы Мали оперативный звязок
written right now and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegrams okrim video also interesting and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we are obliged to you to
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
keep constant operational links
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that che will show you about This
незалежно в того чи покаже вам про Цей
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
subscribe and
подпишись а